Margaret Witter Fuller Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Margaret Witter Fuller Papers.
undated, 1903-1956.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Fuller, Margaret Witter, 1875-1954.
4 linear feet.
Margaret Witter Fuller was born 23 January 1872, in Brooklyn, New York. In 1874, the family moved to Norwich, Connecticut. Miss Fuller resided in Norwich for many years. A prolific writer, she authored many poems, plays and novels. Miss Fuller died 1 February 1954 in Boston, MA.
MSS19980202
Biography
Margaret Witter Fuller was born 23 January 1872, in Brooklyn, New York. She was the daughter of Captain James Ebenezer and Rebecca P. (Hope) Fuller. In 1874, the family moved to Norwich, Connecticut. Miss Fuller> resided in Norwich for many years. A prolific writer, she authored many poems, plays and novels. Her published works include A New England Childhood (1916), Alma (1927), and The Complete History of the Deluge, in Verse and Pictures (1936). One of Miss Fuller's plays, Overnight, was performed (1935) in Norwich, (CT) and was favorably reviewed in the Norwich Bulletin. Miss Fuller died 1 February 1954 in Boston, MA.
Scope and Content
The collection contains manuscripts of poetry, plays, lyrics and fiction, as well as correspondence and notes. Although the author changed the titles of her work more than once, all manuscript materials are filed alphabetically by the title as it appears on the documents or as otherwise indicated by the author.
Arrangement
Series I: Personal Papers ( undated, 1937-1951 )
Series II: Correspondence ( undated, 1903-1956 )
Series III: Writings ( undated, 1910-1952 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary collections. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Bibliography
Warfel, Harry R.. American Novelists for Today. Westport, CT: Greenwood Press, 1972.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
American literature—20th century.; American poetry—20th century.; American drama—20th century.; Connecticut—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Norwich (Conn.)—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Poems.; Scripts.; Fiction.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Personal Papers.; Publications.; Illustrations.; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.
Occupations:
Author.; Playwright.; Poet.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Personal Papers, undated, 1937-1951
  - Biographical Materials, undated, 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Maps, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Norwich Players, undated, 1937-1951 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Uncle's Ledger, undated (Box 3:, Folder 5-7)
- Series II: Correspondence, undated, 1903-1956
  - Unknown, 1949 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Contracts and Royalties, undated, 1910-1956 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Family, 1903-1938 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - General, undated, 1911-1956 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Hopkins, Edwin, 1936-1939 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Huntington, Samuel Property, 1952-1953 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Penniman, James and Josiah, undated, 1923-1939 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Publishers, undated, 1922-1939 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Publishers, 1940-1956 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - State Police, undated, 1940-1947 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
- Series III: Writings, undated, 1910-1952
  - Criticisms, undated, 1910-1952 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Subseries A: Novels and Stories, undated, 1949
    - Ah, An American!, 1949 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Bibliography of Stedman, Edmund C., undated (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Complete History of the Deluge, undated (Box 1:, Folder 21)
      - Woodblock, undated (Box 3:, Folder 22)
    - Free Country chapter II, undated (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Golden Roof reviews, undated (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - Notes for Stories, undated (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - One World at a Time Proofs, undated (Box 3:, Folder 26)
    - Same Scaffolding 4th copy, undated (Box 1:, Folder 27)
    - Scaffold of Stars (throw out), undated (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - This Awakening last chapter, undated (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - Untitled chapters, undated (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    - Untitled stories, undated (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Subseries B: Lyrics, undated
    - Lyrics, undated (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - Folio E, undated (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    - “O Blessed Font”, undated (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - Subseries C: Plays, undated, 1941
    - And Why Not Love 2nd copy, 1941 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
    - Dream in Aveyron, undated (Box 1:, Folder 36)
    - Dumas Entertains first copy, 1941 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
    - Free Country, undated (Box 1:, Folder 38)
    - Free Country (throw out), 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
    - Great Joy revised, 1939 (Box 1:, Folder 40)
    - One More Fling 4th draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 41)
    - Overnight, undated (Box 1:, Folder 42)
    - Posing in Paris, undated (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - Recent Mrs. Gilbert, undated (Box 2:, Folder 44)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 2:, Folder 45)
    - Witch Finder duplicate, corrected, 1941 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
  - Subseries D: Poetry and Verses, undated, 1938-1940
    - Few Sonnets, 1939-1940 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - “Folio F”, undated (Box 2:, Folder 48)
    - “Heritage”, undated (Box 2:, Folder 49)
    - Poetry, early, undated (Box 2:, Folder 50)
    - Poems, undated, 1938-1940 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
    - Sonnets and Songs TS, undated (Box 2:, Folder 52)
      - Proofs, undated (Box 3:, Folder 53)
    - Unfinished verse, undated (Box 2:, Folder 54)